<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Acme Packing Company</title>
	<subtitle type="text">Your best source for quality Green Bay Packers news, rumors, analysis, stats and scores from the fan perspective.</subtitle>

	<updated>2025-09-03T16:43:03+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" />
	<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/rss/index.xml" />

			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Jon Meerdink</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Wednesday Cheese Curds: Packers ready to begin 2025 campaign]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-daily-links-news/70372/wednesday-cheese-curds-packers-ready-to-begin-2025-campaign" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70372</id>
			<updated>2025-09-03T11:36:29-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-03T11:35:38-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Cheese Curds: Daily Green Bay Packers News And Links" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The regular season is upon us. Tomorrow night, the Micah Parsons-less Dallas Cowboys will face the Super Bowl champion Philadelphia Eagles to kick off the long march to Super Bowl LX, which will hopefully conclude with the Packers raising the Lombardi trophy. If the possibility of the Packers being Super Bowl champs doesn’t get you [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/imagn-25327333.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The regular season is upon us. Tomorrow night, the Micah Parsons-less Dallas Cowboys will face the Super Bowl champion Philadelphia Eagles to kick off the long march to Super Bowl LX, which will hopefully conclude with the Packers raising the Lombardi trophy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the possibility of the Packers being Super Bowl champs doesn’t get you at least a little worked up, perhaps <a href="https://www.packers.com/video/welcome-back-packers-2025-season-trailer">the Packers’ recently released season trailer</a> will do it for you. This was clearly produced well in advance of the Packers’ recent significant roster addition, but there’s a little cameo at the end you may enjoy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But whether you’re excited now or waiting for Sunday to let yourself get hyped, the fact remains: the NFL season is almost here. We’ve almost made it through the long slog of the offseason. Months of speculation and anticipation are now behind us. Only football remains. Bring it on.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://packerswire.usatoday.com/story/sports/nfl/packers/2025/09/03/green-bay-packers-super-bowl-analysis-2025-micah-parsons/85952197007/"><strong>6 reasons why Packers can win Super Bowl in 2025: Parsons vaults Green Bay into contention | Packers Wire</strong></a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You probably didn’t need six whole reasons, but here they are.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.espn.com/nfl/story/_/id/46088393/nfl-green-bay-packers-josh-jacobs-xavier-mckinney"><strong>Jacobs, McKinney have bigger goals for Year 2 with Packers | ESPN</strong></a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Josh Jacobs and Xavier McKinney had tremendous starts to their respective Packers careers, but they’re aiming higher in their second campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.packersnews.com/story/sports/nfl/packers/2025/09/03/micah-parsons-doesnt-have-to-be-reggie-white-for-packers-trade-to-work/85938266007/"><strong>Micah Parsons doesn’t have to be Reggie White for trade to work for Packers | Packers News</strong></a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reggie White is the inevitable comparison, but Tom Silverstein argues he doesn’t even need to be that good to have a comparable impact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.si.com/nfl/packers/onsi/explaining-option-bonuses-which-made-micah-parsons-contract"><strong>Explaining Option Bonuses, Which Made Micah Parsons’ Contract Affordable | Sports Illustrated</strong></a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Breaking down the contract mechanism that makes Micah Parsons’ contract go.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/6593017/2025/09/03/keisean-nixon-packers-top-cornerback/">How Keisean Nixon became the Packers’ No. 1 cornerback, whether you like it or not | The Athletic</a> ($)</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It seems safe to say that nobody expected Keisean Nixon to ever be the Packers’ top cornerback, but here we are.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://apnews.com/article/bolivia-la-paz-miracle-tree-aymara-andean-pachamama-8d20aafb130358562fef6f41b3374e7b"><strong>Devotees say Bolivia’s lightning-struck ‘miracle tree’ conjures luck | Associated Press</strong></a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Anybody want to help the Packers by taking a trip to Bolivia and conjuring up some luck?</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Justis Mosqueda</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Recent backup QB deals mean Malik Willis’ cost will rise]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-news/70358/green-bay-packers-news-malik-willis-quarterback-extension-market-update-2025" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70358</id>
			<updated>2025-09-03T11:10:39-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-03T11:01:30-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Around the NFL" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers depth chart" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers News" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers roster" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers salary cap" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Up until recently, there were very few backup quarterbacks in the NFL who received north of $5 million per year. Even veteran quarterbacks with starting experience, like Jameis Winston ($4 million) and Jimmy Garoppolo ($3 million), came short of that number. Recently, the market has moved, though. Tyson Bagent of the Chicago Bears, who threw [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-2232099525.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.874472540868,100,45.312516279603" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Up until recently, there were very few backup quarterbacks in the NFL who received north of $5 million per year. Even veteran quarterbacks with starting experience, like Jameis Winston ($4 million) and Jimmy Garoppolo ($3 million), came short of that number.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recently, the market has moved, though. Tyson Bagent of the Chicago Bears, who threw all of two passes last season, <a href="https://www.espn.com/nfl/story/_/id/46030016/bears-sign-backup-qb-tyson-bagent-two-year-extension">signed a two-year, $10 million extension a couple of weeks ago</a>. Prior to his new contract, the only backup quarterbacks earning north of $4 million per year were Marcus Mariota ($8 million), Jacoby Brissett ($6.25 million), Zach Wilson ($6 million), Jarrett Stidham ($6 million) and Tyrod Taylor ($6 million) going into the 2025 regular season.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This week, the backup quarterback market moved again, as Davis Mills, C.J. Stroud’s number two in Houston, received a one-year, $7 million extension with the Texans. He’s now the second-highest paid backup quarterback in the league, only behind a former second overall selection who has 74 starts under his belt. Meanwhile, Mills hasn’t started in two full regular seasons (about to be three) and has a career record of 5-19-1.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Green Bay Packers’ backup quarterback at the moment is Malik Willis, who led the team to two victories last season and is set to become an unrestricted free agent in 2026. Because the Packers didn’t extend Willis when the prices for backups were lower, his floor is now probably the $5 million than Bagent, who didn’t have nearly the impact that Willis did in 2024, signed for.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the Packers want to lock Willis up long-term, it would be smart for them to do so sooner rather than later, as there’s potential for the market to move even further. After all, the $25 million year-to-year salary cap increases that we’re seeing in the NFL have to get absorbed somewhere, and backup quarterbacks are more likely to hit the open market than starters at other positions. Ultimately, <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/2025/6/5/24443586/nfl-salary-cap-analysis-cash-spending-post-covid-roger-goodell-2025">it’s the type of players who hit the open market who are more likely to see their salaries significantly increase than the league’s stars</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Green Bay doesn’t want to use future cap space on Willis, they’ll probably look to the 2026 draft for a backup. <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-roster/70004/green-bay-packers-2025-roster-2026-free-agents-update-post-cutdown-cuts">With 19 expiring contracts on the team’s 2026 roster</a>, the Packers will be looking to stack compensatory draft picks for the 2027 season next free agency, rather than signing outside free agents.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For what it’s worth, if Willis received a $5 million to $7 million per year deal with another team in 2026, <a href="https://overthecap.com/compensatory-picks">the league’s compensatory draft formula would award Green Bay with a sixth- to seventh-round pick in 2027</a>, as long as they didn’t sign any free agents who would offset the loss. The man who will negotiate Willis’ next contract, be it with the Packers or not, is Athlete’s First David Mulugheta, who also represents quarterback Jordan Love, edge rusher Micah Parsons, safety Xavier McKinney and defensive end Kingsley Enagbare in Green Bay.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Justis Mosqueda</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How many snaps can Micah Parsons play vs. the Lions?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/analysis/70175/micah-parsons-snap-counts-week-1-khalil-mack-comparison" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70175</id>
			<updated>2025-09-03T12:43:03-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-03T08:39:03-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="By the Numbers" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers Analysis" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers depth chart" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers roster" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s going to be a quick turnaround for Green Bay Packers pass-rusher Micah Parsons to see the field against the Detroit Lions in Week 1. He was traded on August 28th, just 10 days before the Packers’ season opener on September 7th. Because of that, many are wondering, “How many snaps is he actually going [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-1888261577.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s going to be a quick turnaround for Green Bay Packers pass-rusher Micah Parsons to see the field against the Detroit Lions in Week 1. He was traded on August 28th, just 10 days before the Packers’ season opener on September 7th. Because of that, many are wondering, <em>“How many snaps is he actually going to be on the field for?”</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The easiest one-to-one comparison in this situation is what Khalil Mack went through back in 2018. Mack was traded on September 1st and played on September 9th, just an eight-day turnaround. So in this aspect, Parsons actually has the edge. Parsons will also be playing a home game, which means not deleting a day for travel, while Mack traveled to Lambeau Field for his Chicago Bears debut, another factor in this equation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Mack didn’t start for the Bears, he did play a majority of the snaps in that game. In total, he played 42 defensive reps, good for 70 percent of the game. That was his season low in 2018, but it wasn’t extraordinarily low. For reference, he averaged 54.8 defensive snaps in the remaining games of the season, so a dock of about 13ish snaps from his usual rate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mack immediately became a “starter” (even though he played the majority of snaps in Week 1) the following week. In the next three games, he played 48, 50 and 51 reps, pretty close to his snap count in Week 1.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So do I think Parsons is going to be hyper-limited to obvious pass-rushing downs against the Lions? Not if Mack’s turnaround is any indication. Honestly, Parsons could eat a starter’s share worth of snaps this week. For perspective, in substitution-happy Green Bay, starting defensive end Rashan Gary has only played 53 percent and 59 percent of defensive snaps over the last two years. If anything, Parsons playing 70 percent of reps would be an immediate improvement at the position, not a reduction in play for a starter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Will the Packers have their full playbook installed with Parsons and allow him to roam the field in all sorts of places? That’s where I have my doubts. But as far as him actually getting on the field? There shouldn’t be huge limitations. Expect to see him a lot on the edge this week with the linebacker-type blitz fronts showing up more week-by-week.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there’s any “be fast, see ball, go get ball” position in the NFL, it’s edge rusher. How did Mack fare with just one week of practice in Chicago? He posted a sack, an interception for a 27-yard touchdown, a pass breakup, a forced fumble and a fumble recovery.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Honestly, Parsons will probably play more versus Detroit than you think.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Evan &quot;Tex&quot; Western</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Packers Week 1 Odds: Green Bay favored over Lions at Lambeau]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-odds/70349/packers-week-1-odds-lions-lambeau-green-bay-favored-micah-parsons" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70349</id>
			<updated>2025-09-03T08:33:16-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-03T08:35:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers odds" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the NFL initially released its regular season schedule for 2025, the Green Bay Packers were underdogs at home in week one. Hosting the Detroit Lions — who are coming off back-to-back NFC North titles and a 15-2 season last year — is no easy task, and being slight underdogs to that team is nothing [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-2182730832.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When the NFL initially released its regular season schedule for 2025, the Green Bay Packers were underdogs at home in week one. Hosting the Detroit Lions — who are coming off back-to-back NFC North titles and a 15-2 season last year — is no easy task, and being slight underdogs to that team is nothing to be embarrassed about, even if the game is on your home turf.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In mid-May, <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/2025/5/22/24435263/packers-week-1-odds-lions-favored-slightly-in-opener-at-lambeau">the oddsmakers put the Lions as 1.5-point favorites for the opener at Lambeau Field</a>, a game that is the Packers’ first home game in week 1 since 2018. Moneyline bets had the Lions at -120 and the Packers at +102. But in the three-plus months since that time, the line has changed considerably, shifting a whopping four points.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most of that change came immediately after the line was announced. With lots of money coming in on the Packers early on, it quickly shifted to a Packers -1.5 spread. But now, as of Wednesday, <a href="https://sportsbook.fanduel.com/navigation/nfl">the Packers are now 2.5-point favorites at Fanduel Sportsbook</a>, with a moneyline number of -142 against the Lions’ +120.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s the reason for the most recent shift? That’s easy: the Packers have a big new acquisition to unveil on Sunday afternoon, with Micah Parsons’ arrival moving the line another point in the team’s favor. Parsons’ impact on Sunday will be interesting to see, given that he will only have a week or so to learn the team’s defense, but expect him to be a key component of the team’s pass rush in nickel personnel groupings and in obvious passing situations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This also marks the first time that the Packers are favored against the Lions since the season finale in 2022, which was Aaron Rodgers’ final game in green and gold. The Packers, who needed a win to clinch a playoff spot, were favored by five points but lost 20-16 as Dan Campbell’s team completed a season sweep of Green Bay despite being underdogs in both games. Since then, the Lions have been favored in four straight, winning three of four but splitting the games 2-2 against the spread.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Additionally, this game has an over/under total of 47.5 points, one of the higher numbers in week one across the NFL. Several other games match that number, but only one — Ravens vs. Bills on Sunday Night Football — has a bigger number, with that game coming in at 50.5.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Justis Mosqueda</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What are your expectations for Matthew Golden in 2025?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/general/70345/matthew-golden-expectations-2025" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70345</id>
			<updated>2025-09-03T08:11:18-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-03T08:11:18-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="General" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, let’s hear from you guys — shoutout to Revenge4BDU for the idea on this one. In a recent article, I said that rookie first-round receiver Matthew Golden, or at least what his ceiling is this year, is one of my biggest question marks about the Green Bay Packers this season. I’ve seen the summer [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/08/imagn-26915109.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Alright, let’s hear from you guys —<span> <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-roster/70333/green-bay-packers-roster-questions-2025-colby-wooden-javon-bullard?commentID=e8c07ff1-348b-4eba-8595-1f99146f8cf8" target="_blank">shoutout</a></span><a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-roster/70333/green-bay-packers-roster-questions-2025-colby-wooden-javon-bullard?commentID=e8c07ff1-348b-4eba-8595-1f99146f8cf8"> to Revenge4BDU for the idea on this one</a>. In a recent article, I said that rookie first-round receiver Matthew Golden, or at least what his ceiling is this year, is one of my biggest question marks about the Green Bay Packers this season.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve seen the summer highlights. I’m very excited about him, but I’ve been down this road with Packers rookies before, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let’s lay it all out there.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I still think that Jayden Reed is going to command the full-time role in the <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/2025/3/18/24388844/green-bay-packers-analysis-jayden-reed-slot-outside-personnel-splits">slot in three-receiver looks</a>, which he’s held down since he got to Green Bay. With that being said, the fact that <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-injuries/70073/green-bay-packers-news-jayden-reed-injury-update-foot-jones-fracture">he does have a Jones fracture</a> has me uneasy about projecting him to stay healthy for 17 regular-season games (and hopefully the playoffs). If Reed is ever out, Golden should be the next man up in the slot, as Romeo Doubs, Dontayvion Wicks and Savion Williams are more outside receivers than guys you can lineup everywhere on the field.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With that being said, I do think Golden will get a lot of snaps on the outside, too, as long as Reed is healthy, in part because both Wicks and Williams missed a lot of camp with injury. I wouldn’t be shocked at all if Golden starts every game as an outside receiver, opposite of Doubs, until Christian Watson comes off the physically unable to perform list. I think Golden, Doubs and Wicks will be in a pretty healthy rotation, though.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once Watson comes back, I have no idea how the team will handle the situation. The Packers are still a run-first team that rotates their receivers a lot, outside of Reed in specific formations. Maybe it’s just a four-man outside rotation with Doubs, Watson, Golden and Wicks, and Reed and Golden trading off in the slot? My guess is as good as yours right now.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tell me what you think will happen with Golden this year. Feel free to voice your opinion in the comment section.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">[P.S.: I tried to draft Golden in my girlfriend’s work’s fantasy league yesterday, but he was snatched up right before I was comfortable taking him. If he goes off, I will never forgive myself.]</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Justis Mosqueda</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[A new NCAA lawsuit could reshape the NFL Draft]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-draft/70341/nfl-draft-2026-news-ncaa-lawsuit-eligibility-vanderbilt-football" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70341</id>
			<updated>2025-09-03T07:46:03-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-03T07:46:03-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers Draft" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the biggest shocks I saw this weekend from a college football standpoint was that quarterback T.J. Finley, after Week 1 had already started, was planning on transferring to Georgia State. After seeing the news, I thought to myself, “There’s just no way that Finley still has eligibility remaining.” Finley is now on his [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-2232684074.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the biggest shocks I saw this weekend from a college football standpoint was that quarterback T.J. Finley, after Week 1 had already started, was planning on transferring to Georgia State. After seeing the news, I thought to myself, “There’s just no way that Finley still has eligibility remaining.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finley is now on his fifth school in six seasons, which feels much longer because he’s been a starter at every stop, starting with his true freshman season: LSU, Auburn, Texas State, Western Kentucky and now Georgia State. So how is Finley still eligible? Because he utilized the freebie year that college football afforded for the 2020 season and received a redshirt season. This is your reminder that all of the Covid year players have still not cycled out of the sport, but it’s nearing the end for them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, <a href="https://x.com/NicoleAuerbach/status/1963003844255744467">according to NBC Sports’ Nicole Auerbach</a>, more players want in the extra eligibility action. Per Auerbach, two Vanderbilt football players have filed a class action lawsuit against the NCAA over eligibility rules. The hope for them is that they earn the potential to play five seasons over five years of eligibility, rather than the four seasons over five seasons standard currently set by the NCAA.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Earlier this year, Vanderbilt quarterback Diego Pavia, who isn’t involved in the newest lawsuit against the NCAA, won a case where he successfully claimed that the NCAA’s counting of junior college seasons toward players’ eligibility is a violation of the Sherman Antitrust Act. Now on his third school in his sixth overall year as a starter, Pavia returned to be the Commadores’ quarterback for the 2025 season.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what does this mean for the NFL and the Green Bay Packers? Well, first of all, if the new lawsuit is successful, then we’re almost certainly going to see fewer players available in the upcoming draft. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Back in 2019, before eligibility tolled for the 2020 season and NIL payments were rampant in college football, <a href="https://www.espn.com.sg/nfl/draft2019/story/_/id/25448136/2019-nfl-draft-underclassmen-declaration-tracker-full-list-prospects">135 underclassmen declared for that draft class</a>. Last year, <a href="https://www.nfl.com/news/fifty-five-players-granted-special-eligibility-for-2025-nfl-draft">only 55 non-graduates declared early for the 2025 draft</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With big money being spent at the college level, it’s hard to blame these kids, either. For example, former Texas quarterback Quinn Ewers, who was drafted in the seventh round in April, <a href="https://247sports.com/college/texas/longformarticle/sources-texas-qb-quinn-ewers-turned-down-an-8-million-nil-offer-to-transfer-in-deciding-to-enter-nfl-draft-244225808/">reportedly turned down an $8 million offer to transfer to another program for the 2025 season</a>. For perspective, that’s roughly the same Year 1 cashflow that first-round pick Josh Simmons will make ($8.2 million) this year on his rookie deal. Over the next three years of Simmons’ contract, he’ll earn $6.52 million total ($2.17 million per year). Ewers, whose only guarantees in his rookie contract are his $131,576 signing bonus, is probably regretting his decision not to stay in college for that extra year. He’s just one of three underclassmen quarterbacks to be drafted outside of the first round over the last three draft classes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In this post-Covid, post-NIL era, Packers general manager Brian Gutekunst has repeatedly stated over and over again that he enjoyed plucking young talent in late rounds of these more well-developed classes. Success stories include fifth-round pick Dontayvion Wicks, fifth-round pick Kingsley Enagbare, fifth-round pick T.J. Slaton, sixth-round pick Karl Brooks, sixth-round pick Isaiah McDuffie, seventh-round pick Carrington Valentine and seventh-round pick Rasheed Walker. While none of them are All-Pros, they are certainly value selections for where Green Bay took them. Valentine, going into his third year in the league, for example, is only 23 years old and has 19 starts under his belt heading into 2025. Had he been a prospect in the 2025 draft, <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/2025/4/29/24420061/green-bay-packers-2025-nfl-draft-analysis-cornerback-market-reaches">he probably would have been a second- or third-round pick</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Packers’ scouts, and Gutekunst, <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-draft/70250/green-bay-packers-scouts-week-1-college-football-2025-2026-nfl-draft">are already hard at work on the next draft class</a>. There’s some uncertainty on the horizon about college eligibility, but the good news is that Green Bay has done a pretty good job of leveraging these more well-aged draft classes to find value on Day 3 of the draft. Personally, I wouldn’t mind if the Packers had more of those opportunities. They seem to be adjusting well to this era.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Justis Mosqueda</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The 3 biggest questions for the 2025 Green Bay Packers]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-roster/70333/green-bay-packers-roster-questions-2025-colby-wooden-javon-bullard" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70333</id>
			<updated>2025-09-03T03:39:31-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-03T06:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers Analysis" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers roster" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that the Micah Parsons news has finally settled down a little bit, I want to turn to what the Green Bay Packers’ biggest question marks are going into the upcoming season. Green Bay returns most of its starters from last season, which is one reason why the roster cutdowns were less eventful than in [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-2188772574.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,80.139233978716" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Now that the Micah Parsons news has finally settled down a little bit, I want to turn to what the Green Bay Packers’ biggest question marks are going into the upcoming season. Green Bay returns most of its starters from last season, which is one reason why the roster cutdowns were less eventful than in previous years, but changing situations — be it because of injuries that the Packers are dealing with or the Parsons trade itself — shouldn’t be glanced over.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let’s go ahead and hit on the three biggest questions that I have with the team’s 2025 personnel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">#<strong>1: Is Matthew Golden legit?</strong></p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Jordan Love says rookie WR Matthew Golden is the perfect guy to have a breakout year 🔥 <br><br>“He’s gonna be a guy we’re gonna be trying to get the ball to as much as possible” <a href="https://t.co/ktbXQadoQp">pic.twitter.com/ktbXQadoQp</a></p>&mdash; Hogg (@HoggNFL) <a href="https://twitter.com/HoggNFL/status/1963047358800793842?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With Dontayvion Wicks and rookie third-round pick Savion Williams injured for most of training camp, along with Christian Watson still recovering from his 2024 ACL tear, opportunities were plentiful for first-round rookie receiver Matthew Golden this summer. Given those chances, Golden seemed to impress every day of practice and made some tough catches during the preseason, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the Packers’ Week 1 depth chart dropped earlier this week, <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-depth-chart/70328/green-bay-packers-depth-chart-update-2025-week-1-detroit-lions">Golden was actually named a co-starter</a> alongside Romeo Doubs and Jayden Reed, <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/2025/3/18/24388844/green-bay-packers-analysis-jayden-reed-slot-outside-personnel-splits">who almost exclusively plays in the slot in three-receiver sets</a> in Matt LaFleur’s offense. Considering how much LaFleur likes to play two-tight end sets when both Tucker Kraft and Luke Musgrave have been healthy — which, to be fair, hasn’t been often — it really could be the Doubs and Reed show, primarily, until Watson comes off the physically unable to perform list.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Green Bay wants to be a bully ball team. They don’t throw the ball that much relative to the situations that they’re put in. They’re very heavy at basically every position on offense. But they need a credible speedster on the outside to play that style of football. With Watson out, Golden is going to be tabbed with the task. He’s been great this summer, and if they want to contend for a title, they need him to be that during the regular season, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>#2: Is defensive tackle good enough?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notice I say defensive tackle and not just Colby Wooden. I really do think this is a question for the entire defensive tackle room. Remember, this is the first time that Devonte Wyatt is going to be a full-time starter for the Packers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last year, Green Bay’s preferred defensive tackle duo on early downs was T.J. Slaton and Kenny Clark, who are now playing for the Cincinnati Bengals and Dallas Cowboys, respectively. This year, the expectation is that Wyatt will start at three-technique and Wooden will start at nose tackle. With that being said, both Georgia rookies, Warren Brinson and Nazir Stackhouse, can credibly play nose tackle for the team if Wooden’s reshaping of his body (he was 273 pounds at the 2023 combine and is still listed at that weight by the team) doesn’t pan out.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pass-rush production has never been the issue for Wyatt, but he did have a 51.9 run defense grade last year per Pro Football Focus. Meanwhile, Wooden had a 47.8 overall grade (160th among 220 qualifying defensive tackles) and just a 46.5 run defense grade.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>#3: Who is going to play in the slot?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While it was good that the Packers were able to get second-round rookie Javon Bullard on the field for them last year, the results were a mixed bag, to say the least. In pass coverage, he scored a 46.9 grade per PFF, which ranked 141st out of 171 safeties, even though he played primarily in the slot once fourth-round rookie Evan Williams displaced him from the safety position.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="cy" dir="ltr">Bullard wyd <a href="https://t.co/14sbjRVohW">pic.twitter.com/14sbjRVohW</a></p>&mdash; Justis Mosqueda (@JuMosq) <a href="https://twitter.com/JuMosq/status/1954439431232135316?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 10, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-depth-chart/69704/green-bay-packers-depth-chart-2025-preseason-snap-counts-final">Bullard got all of eight snaps in the slot this preseason</a>, which included the lowlight from above, where he failed to fill his gap assignment, didn’t touch the ball carrier until the Jets back was double-digit yards downfield and ultimately, the back gaining that steam ended up injuring Bullard’s teammate, fellow safety Zayne Anderson.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We saw some big improvements this preseason from young players who didn’t look good last year, notably linebacker Ty’Ron Hopper, but Bullard hasn’t been among that group. With cornerback Nate Hobbs, <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/2025/4/14/24408497/green-bay-packers-news-nfl-slot-cornerback-contracts-2025-nate-hobbs-jalen-pitre-kyler-gordon">whose contract is step-in-step with the current slot cornerback market</a>, injured, Bullard might end up starting in the slot early in the season, if not for the whole year. The only other player on the Packers’ roster who has experience there, beyond Bullard and Hobbs, is outside cornerback Keisean Nixon, who hasn’t been practicing at the position for essentially a calendar year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not like Green Bay has cornerbacks in droves, either. After Nixon and Hobbs, who at minimum will be playing outside cornerback in base 4-3 looks, the next men up are Carrington Valentine, who has been good in coverage in the past, and receiver-turned-cornerback Bo Melton. The Packers elected to keep outside cornerbacks Nate Hobbs and Micah Robinson, a rookie draft pick who is now on the practice squad, on their initial 53-man roster over slot cornerbacks Kalen King and Corey Ballentine at the roster cutdown.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Justis Mosqueda</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Packers name WR Matthew Golden a starter on Week 1 depth chart]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-depth-chart/70328/green-bay-packers-depth-chart-update-2025-week-1-detroit-lions" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70328</id>
			<updated>2025-09-02T16:30:19-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-02T16:30:19-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers depth chart" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers roster" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the first time this regular season, the Green Bay Packers have updated their depth chart. Based on what we saw out of the team this summer, it&#8217;s a pretty accurate representation of where the team is. Here are a couple of interesting notes: Below is the full depth chart:]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-2219551118.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,91.850653916467" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For the first time this regular season, the Green Bay Packers have updated their depth chart. <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-roster/69996/green-bay-packers-depth-chart-2025-post-cutdowns-cuts">Based on what we saw out of the team this summer</a>, it&#8217;s a pretty accurate representation of where the team is.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Here are a couple of interesting notes:</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Ohhh baby, that was Golden <a href="https://t.co/K3z3JoYNlU">pic.twitter.com/K3z3JoYNlU</a></p>&mdash; Green Bay Packers (@packers) <a href="https://twitter.com/packers/status/1959349898765013335?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Rookie first-round pick Matthew Golden is listed as a starting outside receiver over veterans Dontayvion Wicks and Malik Heath. Golden played well throughout training camp, but it’s still rare that the Packers throw the keys to a rookie draft pick. He’s the only starter among the 2025 draft class.</li>



<li>Rasheed Walker, who said that he would be the team’s starting left tackle yesterday in the locker room after practice, is indeed listed as the Packers’ top left tackle. Sean Rhyan is listed as the preferred right guard, so you can expect Jordan Morgan to rotate in off the bench at left tackle and right guard this season. Last year, Rhyan and Morgan split time at right guard when healthy.</li>



<li>Micah Parsons is officially listed as a defensive end, which will probably help him down the line if the Packers ever want to franchise tag him. Both Lukas Van Ness and Kingsley Enagbare are listed as second-string defenders at defensive end, leaving Brenton Cox Jr. as a third-stringer. Cox has been behind Enagbare on the depth chart throughout training camp.</li>
</ul>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The most improved Packer from last year is Ty&#039;Ron Hopper (LB #59) <a href="https://t.co/VtoMpyf2BI">pic.twitter.com/VtoMpyf2BI</a></p>&mdash; Justis Mosqueda (@JuMosq) <a href="https://twitter.com/JuMosq/status/1957121806697218432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 17, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Isaiah McDuffie is the team’s listed third starting linebacker, so don’t think that Ty’Ron Hopper’s hot summer will mean that the team is working to get him on the field on defense. Right now, he’s just a good backup who plays special teams for Green Bay.</li>



<li>The Packers’ listed starters in the return game are Keisean Nixon (kick return) and Jayden Reed (punt return). <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-roster/69777/green-bay-packers-punt-returner-2025-jayden-reed-mecole-hardman-keisean-nixon-analysis">It’s going to be tough for the Packers to ever get better at punt returner</a>, considering how big head coach Matt LaFleur likes his receivers.</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is the full depth chart:</p>
<img src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/Gz3hSR2XEAAu7ee.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>rcon14</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s now or never for Colby Wooden]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/green-bay-packers-roster/70286/green-bay-packers-analysis-colby-wooden-kenny-clark-replacement" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70286</id>
			<updated>2025-09-02T16:11:38-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-02T16:11:38-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers roster" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Kenny Clark sent to the Dallas Cowboys as part of the compensation for superstar pass rusher Micah Parsons, a wide-open role exists next to Devonte Wyatt in the Packers&#8217; starting lineup. It’s always hard to glean too much from pre-season reps. Teams are often trying to make roster judgements moreso than preparing for the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/08/gettyimages-2194078620.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,80.241878779356" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">With Kenny Clark sent to the Dallas Cowboys as part of the compensation for superstar pass rusher Micah Parsons, a wide-open role exists next to Devonte Wyatt in the Packers&#8217; starting lineup. It’s always hard to glean too much from pre-season reps. Teams are often trying to make roster judgements moreso than preparing for the regular season, but if training camp seems to be any indication, it appears that the starting nose tackle job will initially fall to Colby Wooden, though the unoffical depth chart on the team’s website still has Clark’s old spot vacant, and the depth chart did not break things down by nose tackle and three-technique.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To say this career path is surprising for Wooden is perhaps the understatement of the century. Wooden’s position in the NFL was always up in the air during the draft process, with The Athletic’s Dane Brugler splitting the difference in his annual draft guide, placing him with the defensive tackles, but noting his ability to play as a base down defensive end, 4i, or three-technique.</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">A three-year starter at Auburn, Wooden was the starting defensive end in former defensive coordinator Jeff Schmedding’s four-man front, although most of his snaps came inside the offensive tackle as 4i or three-technique. His production improved each of the last three seasons and he is one of only nine Tigers to<br>reach 30 career tackles for loss over the last 25 years. Wooden is very active off the ball with the lower-body agility and limb quickness to play in gaps. However, his block destruction is undeveloped and he must do a better job staying on schedule to make a living battling NFL blockers. Wooden isn’t consistently disruptive when rushing from the outside, but he can set the edge or reduce down where his rush skills are more effective on the interior. He offers position flexibility as a rotational base end or three-technique as an NFL rookie capable of ascending to starter.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wooden showed up to the combine at just 273 pounds, nearly the exact same as Packers defensive end Lukas Van Ness. He then mildly bulked up by his pro day to 278 pounds, but still well short of what you would expect even for a penetrating three-technique (typically north of 290 pounds). We know that last off-season, Wooden bulked up to 290 pounds when the Packers switched from a base 3-4 to a base 4-3. Since there was no 4i/five-technique role for him to play on base down anymore, he changed his body to play the three-technique full-time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite adding the weight for the scheme change, Wooden played an even lesser role in his second season than he did as a rookie, totaling only 260 defensive snaps. The snaps he did play were largely uneventful, as well, with Wooden generating just a 5% pressure rate and being a negative in the run game.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After a disappointing sophomore campaign, many, including yours truly, expected Wooden to be on the chopping block this season. With Wyatt and Karl Brooks occupying the three-technique spots, playing time was going to be hard to come by, and with TJ Slaton leaving in free agency, Green Bay was bound to try and add some more beef to the nose tackle room. The draft did not fall particularly kindly for Green Bay to resolve the beef shortage on the defensive interior, however, and they were only able to snag nose tackle Warren Brinson in the sixth round and his Georgia teammate, Nazir “Big Sleepy” Stackhouse, as a priority undrafted free agent. And then, all of a sudden, Colby Wooden was getting backup nose tackle snaps in camp and in the pre-season.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, because the Green Bay Packers website never updates any sort of body measurement, we don’t know how big Colby Wooden is at this point in time. I’d comfortably venture that Wooden is north of 300 pounds at this point, since playing nose tackle at anything short of 305 is almost unheard of, even in an even front where you’re mostly playing the 1-tech rather than a true 0.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Watching back his pre-season film, and it sure still looks like Colby Wooden, albeit with a bit more weight. He still has the quickness where he can force a run stop on occasion. Like here, where he works against the flow of inside zone to stop Isaiah Davis for a short gain.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/O62uMBIR5Z">pic.twitter.com/O62uMBIR5Z</a></p>&mdash; rcon14 (@rcon14) <a href="https://twitter.com/rcon14/status/1962957185282879741?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When a lineman gets his hands on him, though, he’s liable to get washed out, and this particularly became a problem on outside zone, where he was getting dislodged and leaving cutback lanes too often. There are multiple examples of this across the pre-season, some worse than others. This isn’t even the worst offender, but he just seems too easily moved in a lot of cases, even with this rep coming at the three-tech in an under-front. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" data-conversation="none"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/G572Sz0K42">pic.twitter.com/G572Sz0K42</a></p>&mdash; rcon14 (@rcon14) <a href="https://twitter.com/rcon14/status/1962957651924414676?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I do want to highlight a rep, when Green Bay was in an under-front, where he took the center for a walk on one of these. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" data-conversation="none"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/lqD4PQOpFz">pic.twitter.com/lqD4PQOpFz</a></p>&mdash; rcon14 (@rcon14) <a href="https://twitter.com/rcon14/status/1962958140250464655?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the whole, when Wooden was able to win quickly with his hands, his quickness was able to show up. He did have a couple of solid plays of holding his water and generating a stop, like this one. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" data-conversation="none"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/1JSDQ03RVI">pic.twitter.com/1JSDQ03RVI</a></p>&mdash; rcon14 (@rcon14) <a href="https://twitter.com/rcon14/status/1962958442961744324?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 2, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The pre-season tape was a mixed bag for Wooden. There are too many snaps where he still looks like an undersized defensive tackle trying to win against guards. PFF pre-season grades are going to be the ultimate ‘grain of salt’ for sure, but his 55 overall grade and 52 run defense grade are not encouraging overall. My primary concern with the defense is just that the DT room ends up being too small, since none of Wyatt, Wooden, or Brooks is going to rack up a lot of wins from holding their gaps. Getting washed around could leave a lot of traffic that gets in the way of Quay Walker and Edgerrin Cooper doing what they do best as run-and-chase linebackers. On the plus side, finding run-stuffing nose tackle types around the trade deadline is typically a relatively inexpensive purchase to make. It’s either that, or someone like Warren Brinson better be ready for a lot of game time.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dusty Evely</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Micah Parsons film against the Packers’ 2025 opponents]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/packers-film-room-tape-study/70237/micah-parsons-film-study-packers-2025-opponents" />
			<id>https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/?p=70237</id>
			<updated>2025-09-02T12:47:33-04:00</updated>
			<published>2025-09-02T13:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Green Bay Packers Analysis" /><category scheme="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com" term="Packers Film Room" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you haven’t already heard, the Green Bay Packers now retain the services of one Micah Parsons. He has been in the NFL for four years, so I wanted to take a look at how he has performed against the teams on the Packers’ schedule this season. Of the 14 teams on the schedule this [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-2232778283.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>
		</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you haven’t already heard, the Green Bay Packers now retain the services of one <a href="https://www.acmepackingcompany.com/packers-film-room-tape-study/70128/green-bay-packers-film-room-micah-parsons">Micah Parsons</a>. He has been in the NFL for four years, so I wanted to take a look at how he has performed against the teams on the Packers’ schedule this season.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of the 14 teams on the schedule this year, Parsons has faced 12 of them. The only two teams the Packers play this year that Parsons has not faced are the Cowboys (naturally) and the Steelers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So let’s take a look at the Packers’ schedule through the lens of what Micah Parsons has done against them. I’ll mention the games played, then give his per-game averages. Was this basically just an excuse to post a bunch of Micah Parsons clips I’ve gathered over the past week? You betcha!</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 1: Detroit Lions</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">2 games, averaging 1.0 sacks, 1.5 QB Hits, 1.0 TFLs (Tackles for Loss), 19.6% Pressure Rate, 2.5 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Lions 2022-07 Q4 01:29b Sack" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tkLvth4n3WQ?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 2: Washington Commanders</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">8 games, averaging 1.3 sacks, 1.9 QB Hits, 1.1 TFLs, 20.1% Pressure Rate, 5.0 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Commanders" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f6xaZ--DAno?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 3: at Cleveland Browns</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">1 game, averaging 1.0 sacks, 5.0 QB Hits, 1.0 TFLs, 18.8% Pressure Rate, 2.0 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Browns" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yYp9abLeNZk?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 4: at Dallas Cowboys</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No games against</p>
<img src="https://platform.acmepackingcompany.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2025/09/gettyimages-2231581422.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0.010175010175011,100,99.97964997965" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 6: Cincinnati Bengals</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">2 games, averaging 1.0 sacks, 3.5 QB Hits, 1.0 TFLs, 21.1% Pressure Rate, 6.0 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Bengals" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SxWQvYQwRC0?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 7: at Arizona Cardinals</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">2 games, averaging 0.5 sacks, 1.5 QB Hits, 1.5 TFLs, 22.9% Pressure Rate, 3.5 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons 2023-03 Q3 00:17b Sack" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cg6qCzrjoCQ?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 8: at Pittsburgh Steelers</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No games against</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 9: Carolina Panthers</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">3 games, averaging 1.8 sacks, 2.0 QB Hits, 1.7 TFLs, 30.0% Pressure Rate, 4.7 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Panthers" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZOU-lR4QolU?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 10: Philadelphia Eagles</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">7 games, 0.7 sacks, 1.1 QB Hits, 0.9 TFLs, 18.5% Pressure Rate, 4.3 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Eagles" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QrIEA_lihg4?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 11: at New York Giants</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">8 games, 0.6 sacks, 1.6 QB Hits, 0.8 TFLs, 16.2% Pressure Rate, 3.3 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Giants" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/loFZTf5Pv3A?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 12: Minnesota Vikings</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">2 games, averaging 1.0 sacks, 3.0 QB Hits, 2.5 TFLs, 27.0% Pressure Rate, 2.5 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Vikings 2022-11 Q1 13:52b Sack fumble" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DpULkb21E-s?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 13: at Detroit Lions</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">2 games, averaging 1.0 sacks, 1.5 QB Hits, 1.0 TFLs, 19.6% Pressure Rate, 2.5 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Lions 2022-07 Q4 00:58b Sack fumble" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8GnCLiEha_M?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 14: Chicago Bears</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">1 game, averaging 0.0 sacks, 0.0 QB Hits, 0.0 TFLs, 15.0% Pressure Rate, 1.0 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Bears 1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IcPXdB88nZ0?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 15: at Denver Broncos</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">1 game, averaging 2.5 sacks, 3.0 QB Hits, 3.0 TFLs, 50.0% Pressure Rate, 3.0 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Broncos" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nDLKoFCsPPY?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 16: at Chicago Bears</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">1 game, averaging 0.0 sacks, 0.0 QB Hits, 0.0 TFLs, 15.0% Pressure Rate, 1.0 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Bears 2" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_HYE52bdiME?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 17: Baltimore Ravens</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">1 game, averaging 0.0 sacks, 1.0 QB Hits, 0.0 TFLs, 26.7% Pressure Rate, 2.0 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Ravens" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TXAVVGyBfIo?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Week 18: at Minnesota Vikings</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">2 games, averaging 1.0 sacks, 3.0 QB Hits, 2.5 TFLs, 27.0% Pressure Rate, 2.5 Quick Pressures</p>
<div class="youtube-embed"><iframe title="Parsons Vikings 2022-11 Q2 01:05b Sack" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eSz5UxJRmPA?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer *; clipboard-write *; encrypted-media *; gyroscope *; picture-in-picture *; web-share *;"></iframe></div>
<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">For fun, let’s just take his per-game average for these games and think about what the 2025 numbers may look like. For the two teams he hasn’t faced, I just used his career averages (0.8 sacks, 1.8 QB Hits, 1.0 TFLs, 5.3 Pressures, 2.8 Quick Pressures). Under this extremely unscientific method, I’ve got Parsons with 15.1 sacks, 33.2 QB Pressures, 19.9 TFLs, 90.7 Pressures and 45.3 Quick Pressures. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If we want to focus on how he impacts the QB, we can look at Total Pressures by adding Sacks, QB Hits &amp; Pressures. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By that quick-and-dirty metric (small sample size disclaimer and all that), Parsons’ toughest match-up is the Bears (-4.9 pressures per game compared to his career averages), and his most favorable match-up is the Bengals (+7.1 pressures per game compared to his career averages). On the whole, this slate of teams sees Parsons +4.2 in pressures over his career average.</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">Albums listened to: Halsey &#8211; <em>Badlands</em>; Lucy Dacus &#8211; <em>Forever is a Feelin</em>g; Godspeed You! Black Emperor &#8211; <em>Asunder, Sweet and Other Distress</em>; Ghostface Killah &#8211; <em>Supreme Clientele 2</em>; Margo Price &#8211; <em>Hard Headed Woman</em>; Hayley Williams &#8211; <em>Ego Death at a Bachelorette Party</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
